<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qichen zhang</title>
    <description>Crass + SASS.
</description>
    <link>http://qichenzhang.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://qichenzhang.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 01:17:07 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 01:17:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creepy art history.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“And yet… it seems all very trivially unremarkable, still.”&lt;/i&gt; —anonymous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/eve_and_adam.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;via-a-hrefhttpmanwentwrongtumblrcomday20131116-targetblankcreepy-art-historya&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;http://manwentwrong.tumblr.com/day/2013/11/16/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;creepy art history&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 18:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/art/2015/11/23/creepy-art-history.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/art/2015/11/23/creepy-art-history.html</guid>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>gender</category>
        
        
        <category>art</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What about a hit?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A6vjWim6xU6tPjA42GxSp1U&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.complex.com/music/2015/07/hayden-james-new-song-premiere-something-about-you-odesza-remix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;you turn and face me&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 20:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/music/2015/10/05/what-about-a-hit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/music/2015/10/05/what-about-a-hit.html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>electronic</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zeitgeist&#39;s internet tendencies, fig. 1.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;tumblr-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/N-YLnKJrrLNH13AZ_nzxng/48361451574&quot; data-did=&quot;1018fc681d043ce4d96605b2d0fe17e6e7689b16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattbellassai.tumblr.com/post/48361451574&quot;&gt;http://mattbellassai.tumblr.com/post/48361451574&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.assets.tumblr.com/post.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/donnad/cartoon-animals-you-totally-crushed-on-as-a-kid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;original source&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 22:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/internet/2015/10/02/zeitgeist-internet-artifacts-fig-1%20copy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/internet/2015/10/02/zeitgeist-internet-artifacts-fig-1%20copy.html</guid>
        
        <category>buzzfeed</category>
        
        <category>internet</category>
        
        <category>lol</category>
        
        
        <category>internet</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instant messagers + webcames.</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;below-is-a-short-essay-i-wrote-more-than-two-years-ago&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Below is a short essay I wrote more than two years ago.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three summers ago, I became pen pals with a European friend. I was spending the summer in China, and he insisted that we write to each other. Something about email being too insignificant, he said. His main concern—I would read one of his emails, write back something too quickly, and click “send” on a message that had unintelligible typos at best, carrot-eye emoticons at worst. Or I would simply forget to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anachronistic yet romantic prospect of receiving snail mail appealed to my millennial, piddling nostalgia for all things obsolete. I said yes. Before he left, I emailed him my address. I thought he would print out the string of Chinese characters to paste onto the envelope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/20150908_1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Wisconsin postcard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promptly forgot about our exchange. One day, I received an over-Photoshopped card of Kiel, a seaside city in northern Germany. The brief letter on the back contained pedestrian, touristy commentary—the weather was hot, the beer was cold, the Germans were colder—with inquisitions of me interspersed in between my friend’s minutiae. He ended his greeting with a string of hieroglyphic gibberish, parenthetically adding in English, “Here’s my attempt at Chinese. Tell me what it says the next time we meet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I noticed my address. Not pasted onto the card as I had expected, the characters were scrawled childishly in blue ink, dented into the cardboard with a ballpoint pen and indicative of diligent struggle. The stroke order was obviously wrong. The first few characters were spaced miles apart; the next claustrophobically mashed together. The penmanship was altogether atrocious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured he was wracked with anxiety, so I immediately notified my friend of the card’s arrival. “I got it,” I tapped on my laptop. “And your amazing calligraphy skills.” I then sent him a card myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer, he appeared again in my inbox. “THANK YOU FOR THE POSTCARD! In our world of emails, instant messagers &lt;em&gt;[sic]&lt;/em&gt;, webcames &lt;em&gt;[sic]&lt;/em&gt;, I still prefer postcards and letters… by FAR!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/20150908_2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Wisconsin sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing what technology was available to us, we were impractical Luddites. But I couldn’t ignore the parallels between the arbitrariness of my friend’s inane pictographs and the randomness of his electronic mistakes. How different were his nonsensical strokes in ink from his haphazard typos in Gmail? After all, the readability of both messages was dubious. Only one, however, was intentional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely has the banality “it’s the thought that counts” struck me as inspirational. Consider me charmed to have found its elusive moment of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/20150908_3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Walking in Tokyo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/relationships/2015/09/08/instant-messagers-and-webcames.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/relationships/2015/09/08/instant-messagers-and-webcames.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luddism</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>relationships</category>
        
        
        <category>relationships</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A serious consideration of the facts.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Re: model minority-ism and facetious arguments intended to silence people of color, an excerpt from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mocanyc.org/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Museum of Chinese in America&lt;/a&gt;’s permanent exhibit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;even-people-who-are-sympathetic-to-civil-rights-in-general-including-other-people-of-color-sometimes-resist-mentioning-civil-rights-and-asian-americans-together-in-the-same-sentence-it-is-as-if-asian-american-civil-rights-concerns-can-be-ruled-out-categorically-without-the-need-for-serious-consideration-of-the-facts-because-everyone-knows-that-asian-americans-are-prospering-frank-h-wu-legal-scholar&quot;&gt;“Even people who are sympathetic to civil rights in general, including other people of color, sometimes resist mentioning civil rights and Asian Americans together in the same sentence. It is as if Asian American civil rights concerns can be ruled out categorically without the need for serious consideration of the facts, because everyone knows that Asian Americans are prospering.” —Frank H. Wu, legal scholar&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;『包括有色人种在内的民权支持者，有时也不肯将民权与亚裔美人共同探讨。仿佛亚裔美国人相关的民权问题可以完全置之不理，无须慎重考虑事实，就因为所有人都认定亚裔美人个个功成名就。』 — 吴华扬，法律学者&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/race/2015/08/23/serious-consideration-of-the-facts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/race/2015/08/23/serious-consideration-of-the-facts.html</guid>
        
        <category>race</category>
        
        <category>Chinese</category>
        
        <category>criticism</category>
        
        
        <category>race</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll remember 1995.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Molly Nilsson’s music video for her latest single “1995” from the forthcoming &lt;em&gt;Zenith&lt;/em&gt; LP just dropped today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is, unequivocally, everything I had hoped for and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X9ukSm5gmKk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows 95, you’re long gone but I’m still alive 
I’ve gone so far, not even knowing how  
I suppose the world is so much smaller now


the plans that you made  
when you still had the time  
I’ve saved all the things  
that you left behind  
but by now I guess I’d consider them all mine


windows 95, is only a metaphor for what I feel inside 
although I’m older now
there’s still an emptiness 
that’s never letting go somehow


have you ever walked into what seemed
to be somebody else’s dream? 
and though the time won’t let you pass
it keeps you looking through the glass
looking through the glass


1995
they call the year the future was to arrive 
but back in 1995 
we thought we were standing on the threshold 
to the end of time 
(and we still do)
so what’s wrong with living in the past? 
it just happens to be the place I saw you last 
and what’s wrong with living in a dream? 
that one day the echo answers
deep inside of me


I’ll remember 1995 
I’ll remember 1995
I’ll remember 1995
I’ll remember 1995
1995
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;copy-a-hrefhttpmollynilssonlyricstumblrcompost1270031097411995-targetblankmolly-nilssona-2015-all-rights-reserved&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;© &lt;a href=&quot;http://mollynilssonlyrics.tumblr.com/post/127003109741/1995&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Molly Nilsson&lt;/a&gt;, 2015, all rights reserved&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://zeega.com/172878/embed&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 11:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/music/2015/08/18/ill-remember-1995.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/music/2015/08/18/ill-remember-1995.html</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>nostalgia</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Texts from Monday night.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/monday7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 20:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/feminism/2015/07/20/texts-from-monday-night.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/feminism/2015/07/20/texts-from-monday-night.html</guid>
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>power</category>
        
        <category>texts</category>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What feminism is not.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many women I have known, have met, or of whose tweets I’ve briefly scrolled past reject the idea of one definition—of one singular lived experience—of feminism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wholeheartedly agree because I don’t believe a singular feminism exists, even if some theorists want to claim that it does, just given the way human consciousness works. But I’m not a psychologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I am a woman who happens to be alive. And I think that by virtue of being alive, I can offer a simple experiential (although not all-encompassing) process of elimination, as an effort in order to eliminate from popular notions what feminism utterly is absolutely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://persephonemagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/tumblr_nizx6lPzco1u9nolao1_1280-600x461.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;via-savedbythebellhookstumblrcom&quot;&gt;via savedbythebellhooks.tumblr.com&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not the ability to function in a capitalist society. Feminism wholeheartedly rejects capitalism in all that it hurts in its mercenary methodology. Feminism rejects the idea that women’s labor is not valuable and not worthy of material exchange and commercial trade, except for maybe sex work. Feminism is not capitalism in any way, shape, or form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not about overcoming oneself as an individual. Feminism is not about blaming oneself as a woman for not being able to rise to the occasion that men proclaimed to be the occasion to which we should all rise. It is not about overcoming oneself as much as it is about overcoming history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not about being rejected by men. It is not a lashing-out toward a mainstream system that has ultimately rejected women for the majority of history. Feminism is not so self-absorbed such that women would embody a social movement to get the attention of men. Feminism is not a ploy for attention. If it ever could be argued as such, it is because men made it necessary to gain attention in attempts to be treated like human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not watching Tina Fey on TV and thinking that the work is done. Feminism is not watching Tina Fey on TV and thinking that we’ve arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not a white woman who works 90-hour work weeks while a black nanny pushes her children in strollers through the tree-lined park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not “leaning in.” Feminism does not require women to sway in any physical, metaphorical, or patriarchal sense. I do see why the lean-in intellectual apparatus has become such a… almost &lt;em&gt;zeitgest&lt;/em&gt; of our time. This idea that a particular type of labor is privileged and valuable, the publicly visible kind, and that no other type of humanistic project or endeavor can equally provide you the same amount of human respect and self-worth &lt;em&gt;as a woman&lt;/em&gt;. This idea, by conceptual &lt;em&gt;design&lt;/em&gt;, is so attractive because it is so false in its inherent anti-feminist state. This design was so well designed to appeal to our mass-media senses already desensitized by the onslaught of masculinity. We are so accustomed to hating the feminine that “leaning in” provided the masculine rationale to a wholely unattractive brand of intellectual feminism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That “leaning in” could dilute the power of feminism says a lot more about ourselves than it does about feminism itself, though. Its falsehood as feminism constitutes society’s desire for women to be masculine. Leaning in as a mode of feminism is so false because it is entirely unencompassing and entirely unwelcoming and entirely &lt;em&gt;unfeminist&lt;/em&gt;. The idea that women’s labor is only valuable if women’s labor bends to the will of men is not only unfeminist. The idea that a woman’s worth can only come from visible labor that is quantifiable by the capitalist system is not only unfeminist. The idea that a woman must change for others’ expectations of her is not only unfeminist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is violent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This privileging of corporate masculinity—hypermasculinity, more oftentimes than not—rejects the idea that other types of labor are as equally valuable, if not more so. This rejection is not only unfeminist, but it is violent toward women. Equally disturbing just the same, is that Lean In™ feminism is quickly becoming the (god forbid) fifth wave of contemporary feminism, in both a hilarious and heretical sense of the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not feeling emboldened by your own success as a woman while watching other women struggle behind you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not being emboldened by your own success &lt;em&gt;at the expense&lt;/em&gt; of other women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not a neoliberal movement co-opted by people who use it for capitalist gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not a dirty word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not societally accepted, even in 2015. (Why do you think I just had to disclaim that it’s not a dirty word?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meetville.com/images/quotes/Quotation-Bell-Hooks-culture-media-Meetville-Quotes-1377.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not about &lt;em&gt;feeling good&lt;/em&gt; about “being a woman.” (Although it can be. I often feel good about being a feminist and being a woman, but at the same time, I realize my ability to feel good about feminism is not the &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; of feminism.) Feminism is not about massaging the truths that confront every woman daily. Feminism is not about turning a blind eye at the injustices you see everyday in order to keep the peace and make inconvenient truths easier for other people to ignore. It’s not about a sisterhood who gets together to burn bras on the weekends, a sisterhood that dissapates once the sisters return to the mainstream in order to fit in with the expected mold of a docile, gentle, maternal, happy, nice, polite, sweet, agreeable, non-confrontational, non-abrasive, non-angry woman. Feminism is not any of those adjectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is not &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a killjoy. But feminism is also not here for any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all not feminism. These are the very antitheses of feminism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meetville.com/images/quotes/Quotation-Bell-Hooks-life-ignorance-Meetville-Quotes-19710.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are free to use these antitheses on any occasion in which someone tries to tell you what feminism actually &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;. You can help yourself, because I can’t tell you what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 20:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/feminism/2015/06/29/what-feminism-is-not.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/feminism/2015/06/29/what-feminism-is-not.html</guid>
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>Marxist-feminism</category>
        
        <category>labor</category>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For a ruthless criticism of everything existing.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am speaking of a ruthless criticism of everything existing, ruthless in two senses: The criticism must not be afraid of its own conclusions, nor of conflict with the powers that be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;karl-marx-in-a-letter-to-arnold-ruge-september-1843&quot;&gt;—Karl Marx in a letter to Arnold Ruge, September 1843&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I find valuable in critical theory is the unadulterated confrontation of all that causes suffering in modern (or even postmodern) society as we know it today. Critical theorists have no artifically sweetened Splenda view of the way things work sociologically or politically. In the age of &lt;em&gt;populus extrema&lt;/em&gt;, criticism offers a diametrically oppositional view, a view of the populus dystopia too scary for mainstream media (one exception: this reference to our collective “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/lukebailey/lets-fetishise-some-commodities#.nw44q7AnAQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;capitalist hellscape&lt;/a&gt;”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is, at once, anxiously terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, despite the fear it induces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t bury my head under the sand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://40.media.tumblr.com/ba3632854b6c71cdc7f6747f028bdb76/tumblr_nl5mgmrKNJ1svqa72o1_1280.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;via-thedemsocialisttumblrcom&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;via thedemsocialist.tumblr.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marx, Benjamin, Hegel, et al., comfort me, and quite often. Honestly, it’s a lot better than therapy. Harsh words paint harsh colors onto surfaces that most people are happy to leave blandly beige. Which is not to say that beige isn’t real. It very well is—in some &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt;. We live in a state of alienation, which is not the same as our alienation not being real or our lives not being a reflection of our “true” selfhoods. In Marx’s contribution to the Critique of Hegel’s &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Right&lt;/em&gt;, he wrote that religion, as a world theory and a moral institution, is “the fantastic realization of the human being inasmuch as the human being possess no true reality.” We are once living in a time in which we are all alienated, but we do our best to be honest within. We are inverted beings, but only because we live in a state of inversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, this realization that an alienated life can still be a true life is crucial to why it’s comforting. The painful truths that such criticisms of materialism, as well as criticisms of this alienated era of existence, act as both confrontations and self-medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly self-medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://glasstire.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Diaz-HAPPINESS-IS-EXPENSIVE.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;alejandro-diaz-happiness-is-expensive-via-glasstire&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alejandro Diaz, “Happiness is Expensive” via Glasstire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Material accumulation is a funny thing. As a form of currency that’s inherently tied to object fetishism, materialism and the associated mainstream lifestyle that is indicative of our zeitgeist presupposes a sort of societal structure in which external validation is just as significant as any other kind of validation. For example, a survivalist validation (labor in exchange for livelihood). A biologically determinist validation (parental approval as a mode of perpetuating the human species). But this type of sociological, social validation is unique given its root in the specific contradiction of its perceived value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Materially-induced societal validation is inextricably linked to Bourdieu-esque ideas of not only resource acquisition as a human mode of peacocking, but the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; resource acquisition as a mode of ascendant peacocking. The &lt;em&gt;habitus&lt;/em&gt; of moving around or up in the world—oftentimes, &lt;em&gt;others’&lt;/em&gt; worlds—and subjecting oneself to the whims of alienated people just like oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this necessity for external validation and therefore material accumulation, which &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; depends on the existence of object fetishism, then also presupposes that value is absolutely equivalent to Marx’s labor theory of value. On the inversion of the individual in a society that places value on production, Marx noted the correlated effect of consumption: “The &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; you are, the more you have; the less you express your own life, the greater is your &lt;em&gt;alienated&lt;/em&gt; life—the greater is the store of your estranged being. Everything which the political economist takes from you in life and in humanity, he replaces for you in money and in &lt;em&gt;wealth&lt;/em&gt;; and all the things which you cannot do, your money can do.” In other words, what is valuable between us alienated beings in this haphazard capitalist society is our ability to consume. To purchase. To appropriate. To adopt identities based on the objects we fetishize. To subscribe to the idealizations and the imaginations of what life should be, that are not ostensibly manifest in ourselves, but are actually delivered to us, constructed not by us, but solely by others for our easy digestion. Packaged validation, and branded for easy cataloging. We are not expected to add any sort of value back, any sort of recompense for all that we consume. Our contribution may not be validated, and God forbid wasted labor in the age of labor value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a strange time to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TuK4ksjc4Vw/VVGByCu80AI/AAAAAAAAKsE/PT0ZjioJF8Q/s400/Top-001.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;via-personal-message-blog&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;via personal message blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, we can express the trend of our journal in one word: the work of our time to clarify to itself the meaning of its own struggle and its own desires. This is work for the world and for us. It can only be the work of joint forces. It is a matter of confession, no more. To have its sins forgiven mankind has only to declare them to be what they really are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;marx-1843&quot;&gt;—Marx, 1843&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alienated life is terrible, but so are a lot of things. At the least, it can be real. It can be real in the sense that everyone else is alienated in the same societal structure. But innocuously, I open myself to that vulnerable state in which some hope exists for a different value to take hold of the dominant zeitgeist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:leaves:&quot; alt=&quot;:leaves:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f343.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 21:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/philosophy/2015/06/21/for-a-ruthless-criticism-of-everything-existing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/philosophy/2015/06/21/for-a-ruthless-criticism-of-everything-existing.html</guid>
        
        <category>materialism</category>
        
        <category>criticism</category>
        
        <category>Marx</category>
        
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A portrait of the self, in so many (or few) words.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:wave:&quot; alt=&quot;:wave:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44b.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking a lot about design lately at my new(ish) job, I realized how actually vain front-end web development can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/61e5c3fb360bbcbcbb990877a9609582/tumblr_mv4wtbj7cQ1s5e5bko1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Henri&#39;s cripping self-doubt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;via-tumblr&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;via Tumblr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean vain in a strictly derogatory sense. Vanity can serve purposes for objectives beyond mere fuel for the ego’s narcissism. You have fashion industry insiders who need this season’s $800 neoprene purse that looks like it could double as a grocery bag from the neighborhood bodega. You see financiers with their gold/platinum/Einsteinium exclusive reward credit card. (Have I lost you yet?) Regardless of outsider opinions, these socially-driven decisions, based in a form of expression, serve as cues for one’s sense of belonging to a certain community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I hope to illustrate by the word “practical”: I’ve always thought that front-end web development, as a mode of constructing a message or a façade with code, constitutes that same category of social representation toward the external world. It represents the self—at least in some circles—as a material interpretation, and uses symbols of mastery and social cues to communicate that representation to the audience. It’s a face (that’s hopefully less tacky than your LinkedIn profile). At worst, web design and development falls into this same category of narcissistic peacocking. At best, though, it’s kind of a fun way to play with SASS/Ruby/what-have-you while fending off your cat who is trying to catch the mouse on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that was a pretty overanalytical, neurotic, not to mention long-winded, way of saying that I finally got over complaining about how ugly my last site, and got my shit together. (Turns out supporting emoji syntax takes, like, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jemoji&quot;&gt;zero effort&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:expressionless:&quot; alt=&quot;:expressionless:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f611.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off because it’s late. But I leave you with a completely appropriate conclusion of self-representation. My coworker and product designer extraordinaire &lt;a href=&quot;http://shaunpendy.com/&quot;&gt;Shaun Pendergast&lt;/a&gt; made this—and I mean this in the least vainglorious sense—striking portrait of me this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/post images/qcat.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep. Pretty much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 21:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://qichenzhang.com/misc/2015/03/22/a-portrait-of-the-self.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://qichenzhang.com/misc/2015/03/22/a-portrait-of-the-self.html</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>lol</category>
        
        <category>gifs</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
